LINKEDIN GITHUB

OVERVIEW

I am a passionate learner who is constantly searching for new tools and perspectives for understanding the world. I have 4+ years of professional and academic experience with research, statistical analysis, programming, and consulting. While my qualifications are focused on technical skills, I also value qualitative thinking and communication, and thrive in collaborative environments.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & DATA TOOLS

Python (3 Years)

Pandas, Plotly, BeautifulSoup, NumPy, Statsmodels, GeoPandas, Jellyfish, and other libraries. Extensive experience with data analysis, processing, and visualization.

Excel (2 Years)

Macros, VBA, modelling.

R

Used for graduate courses in theoretical and applied econometrics (Tidyverse, ggplot2).

- Stata
- MySQL

EDUCATION

50111014		
•	Master of Arts in Economics – University of British Columbia	(2020-2021)
	4.3/4.33	
•	Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics and Economics – University of British Columbia	(2015-2019)
	3.95/4.33	
•	Exchange Student – Università di Bologna	(2018)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate (Data Scientist) – <u>Deetken Insight Consulting</u>

(Sep 2021-Present)

Distilled and delivered actionable data insights to advise clients (mainly government) in a wide range of fields, including environmental regulation and health IT. Notable engagements include:

Island Health Device Assessment (**Python**). Was responsible for all data analysis. Conducted deep analysis and visualization of health IT infrastructure to understand service bottlenecks. Described by the client as "hands down one of, if not the, best consulting engagements we have commissioned."

BC Greenhouse Gas (GHG) reductions (Excel, Python). Guided the provincial government's implementation of GHG legislation by advising on trade-offs between natural gas ratepayer impacts and emissions reductions. Distilled environmental and financial modelling into intelligible visualizations and insights; assisted in presenting. Led the follow-up project.

Industry Training Authority (**Python**). Conducted extensive data-wrangling and analysis to understand survey results.

• **Graduate Workshop Lead** – University of British Columbia

(Apr 2021-Sep 2021)

Developed and delivered a <u>Web Scraping in Python</u> workshop to an audience of over 50 graduate students, professors, and others.

• Graduate Teaching Assistant – Vancouver School of Economics

(2020-2021)

Game Theory (221) and Econometrics II (326) undergraduate economics courses.

Hosted weekly lectures and office hours for over 100 students in which I demonstrated problem solving and analytical techniques, and taught students to use STATA. Graded assignments and exams.

Undergraduate Research Assistant – Vancouver School of Economics (<u>Viktoria Hnatkovska</u>) (2019-2020)
 Built an <u>NLP framework</u> (Python) to wrangle, categorize, and clean Consumer Price Index data collected as part of a PhD thesis.

Framework used mechanical rules, statistical tests, fuzzy-matching, and machine learning to deliver matching accuracy above 80%

Identified, normalized, and converted units of measurement from plaintext, and recognized unconventional units such as "jars", "sticks", etc.

• **Researcher** – Incumetrics

(2015, 2017, 2018)

Analyzed the impact of AI and self-driving cars in the Auto industry. Researched and analyzed the impact of U.S. gov. small business grants. Analyzed small high-tech companies and condensed technical research into understandable analysis.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

• Statistical Advisor (Pro Bono) – MC Policing Advisory Commission

(2020-Present)

<u>Analyzed and explained</u> racial inequalities in policing patterns to the Civilian Advisory Commission, Chief of Police, and local policymakers.

Designed low-cost experiments to clarify the existence and/or extent of racial bias in policing.

Collaborated with Professor Bruno Jedynak of Portland State University.

• Senior Editor – Iona Undergraduate Journal of Economics

(2017-2019)

Collaborated with authors, professors, and fellow editors to decide which papers would be published. Conducted detailed line edits on said papers.

Intern/Volunteer – Bread for the City

(2014-2015)

• Volunteer – Data For Good (Vancouver)

(2021-Present)

AWARDS

- Outstanding International Student Award UBC
- Go Global International Learning Program Award UBC
- Honorable Mention Graduate Essay Contest 2021 Progressive Economics Forum

LANGUAGES

- English Native Speaker
- Italian Advanced
- Spanish Basic

MISC.

- Chess: 90th percentile of weekly players
- Polymarket Predictions: ≈ 300% portfolio return